Guide to the Adil Jussawalla papers, 1944-2016
Jussawalla, Adil papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Adil Jussawalla papers, 1944-2016
8519
Adil, Jussawalla, 1940-
8.7 cubic feet.
Correspondence, diaries, manuscripts, newspapers, scrapbooks.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, published material, and several manuscripts.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Jussawalla is an Indian poet, critic, and a man of letters. Together with Arvind Krishna Mehrotra he founded the Clearing House press that brought literary modernism to India.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, published material, and several manuscripts.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Jussawalla, Adil, 1940-; Clearing House.; Bombay Poets Archive.
Subjects:
India -- In literature.; Indic literature (English) -- History and criticism.
Form and Genre Terms:
Poetry.; Criticism, interpretation, etc.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Related material located in collection #8511, Arvind Krishna Mehrotra papers.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Writer Files
Series III. Literary Work by Adil Jussawalla
Series IV. Writing by Others
Series V. Personal Writing and Documents
Series VI. Tape Recordings
Series VII. Assorted Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1946-2014
  - Family, 1957-2010
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Firdausi Jussawalla (Brother) Correspondence, 1962-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Jehangir Jussawalla (Father) Correspondence, 1962-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mehera Jussawalla (Mother) Correspondence, 1960-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Family Correspondence, 1957-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Family Correspondence, 1961-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Family Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Family Correspondence, 1968-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Relatives, 1962-2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Poems, letters, and cards from Babbanjee, 1998-2004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Personal (Non-family), 1958-2012
    - Priya Adarkar Note on Dilip Chitre Contribution, 1973-08-02 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lawrence Bantleman Correspondence, 1963-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence concerning Lawrence Bantleman, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dilip Chitre Correspondence, 1967-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Nissim Ezekiel Correspondence, 1963-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Nissim Ezekiel Correspondence, 1968-2014 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Includes scans of book covers from the 1920's and 1940's
    - "Certificate" from John Gawsworth, 1965-03-06 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Fredoon Kabraji Correspondence and Writing, 1970-1987, 2003-2012 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Adi Katrak and Ajit Singh Correspondence and Carcanet Issue, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bruce and Adele King Correspondence, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - T. R. Kini Correspondence and Afro-Asian Echo Issues, 1964-2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Jayanta Mahapatra Correspondence, 1978-2009 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Jayanta Mahapatra Correspondence and Gieve Patel clippings, 1966, 1982-1993, 2007-2012 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Aubrey Menen and Graham Hall Correspondence, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Vijay Nambisan Correspondence, 1990-2007 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Alan Ross Correspondence, 1968-1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Salman Rushdie Correspondence, c. 1968, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Manohar Shetty Correspondence, 1982-2009 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Adil Tyabji Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - T. Wignesan Correspondence and Selected Poems, 1964-1970, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Angus Wilson and Tony Garrett Correspondence, 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Friend Correspondence, 1981-2002 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Ajithan G. Kurup & Padmini Menon Correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cyrus Mistry Correspondence, 1977-2007 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Damodar Prabhu Correspondence, 1980-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Maroher Shetty correspondence, 1988-2008 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Besser Family Correspondence, 1958-2008 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Eunice de Souza Correspondence, 1971-1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Carcanet; Letters from Ajit Singh, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Assorted Personal Correspondence, 1970-1994 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - School-related, 1970, 1977-1979, 1982, 1986, 1994
    Arranged chronologically.
    - School/University correspondence, 1946, 1949, 1956, 1958-1960, 1987, 1989; Access restrictions apply. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Includes original and copy of Adil Jussawalla's birth certificate, both of which are restricted until his death.
    - Correspondence concerning Felsham House, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - School correspondence, 1958, 1962, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Official Correspondence from colleges and schools, 1958-1965, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence with Teachers, 1957-2008 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Oxford-related Correspondence, 1961, 1979, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Oxford friend/acquaintance Correspondence, 1962-2013 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Oxford correspondence, 1963, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      There is only one letter from 2006, the vast majority date to 1963
    - St. Xavier's / University correspondence, 1972-1976, 1982-1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Professional (Non-writing), 1962-2013
    - "Some involvements" (letters regarding writing events, seminars), 1962-2009 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Job Application Correspondence, 1962, 1971, 1974, 1977-1978, 1980, 1982, 1984-1985, 1988-1989, 1990-1992, 1994-1996, 1998, 2000-2001, 2006, 2008, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - International Language Center, London Correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mixed Correspondence - Primarily Writers, 1965-2013 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - Writers, 1966-2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Letters concerning Dilip Chitre's work, 1970-04-17-1970-06-02 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence concerning statements, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Iowa International Writing Program Correspondence and Photos, 1977-1978, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Singapore ACLALS Conference and Writer's Week Correspondence, 1986-03-12-1986-06-28 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Commonwealth Writers Prize Correspondence and Papers, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Loquations Programs, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1999-2009 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and Clippings concerning Arun Kolatkar, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Clearing House and Related Materials, 1962-2008
      - Clearing House Advertisements, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Copy of Subscriber Address Book, Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Clearing House - Pfal Correspondence, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Clearing House - Nissim Ezekiel, 1962-1986 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Clearing House - Assorted Professional Correspondence, 1962-1985 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Assorted Clearing House Letters, 1963-2006 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Clearing House Correspondence - Arvind, 1968-2011 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence with Arvind, 1970-2008 (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Assorted Correspondence, 1971-1983 (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - Clearing House Assorted Correspondence, 1971-2003 (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Clearing House - Jayanta Correspondence, 1971-2004 (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Clearing House - Bills, Logistics, and Receipts, 1973-1989 (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Clearing House - Planning Documents, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Clearing House - Miscellaneous, 1975-1982 (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Clearing House clippings, 1975, 1976, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Comments and reviews of Clearing House books, 1975-1994 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Clearing House beginnings, 1975-2006 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Clearing House and Newground Press Correspondence, 1976-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Clearing House - Letters from Jayanta after "The False Start", 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Clearing House - Letters from Different Years, 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Clearing House bills & receipts, 1976-1989 (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - Clearing House Bills, 1976-1988 (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Clearing House interviews and reviews, 1976-1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Clearing House Letters, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1977-1978, 1984, 1999, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - Clearing House Correspondence (originally sent to one "Jerry"), 1979 (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1979-1986 (Box 9, Folder 42)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 43)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 43)
      - Letters from Darshan and Jehangir, 1980-2010 (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - Clearing Correspondence, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - Clearing House Orders, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - Clearing House covers & order forms, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - Clearing House Correspondence, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 47)
      - Debonair correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Praxis, 1987-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
        Also includes reviews of PRAXIS books
      - Clearing House Letter + Notes, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 48)
      - Clearing House - Arvind Telegram, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Writing Jobs, 1980-1981, 2010
    - E. M. Forster correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence concerning Jian and Floodwaters, 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Publisher Correspondence with Drafts, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Publisher correspondence, 1963-2003 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - SCILET File, 1964-1989 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Land's End Correspondence with P. Lal and Misc. Letters, 1964-1965, 1970-1973, 1976, 1978-1979, 1982-1983, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - Arvind, 1967-2005 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence w/ publishers, editors, 1967-2011 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - New Writing in India Correspondence, 1967, 1973-1974, 1980-1981, 1985, 1988-1994, 1998-2011 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Statements File, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 40)
      Anthology of Indian prose in English
    - Correspondence concerning Angus Wilson Article, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Clearing House Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      Includes one letter from 1986
    - Correspondence with Clients, 1976-1996 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Debonair, 1977-1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - For You Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Most of the documents were created in 1979; Editor was S.V. Vasuder)
    - Sunday Standard File, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      Continuation of dealings with Indian Express, as Sunday Standard is its supplement
    - Debonair, 1982-1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Science Age Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Debonair, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Peguin Books India Ltd. Correspondence, 1973, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Debonair, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Chakravyuha (War) Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Times of India Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Penguin India correspondence & contract, 2002-2006 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Includes packets of unpublished works
    - The Book & The Computer correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Chronological Mixed, 1960-2014
    - Mixed Correspondence, 1960-2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Mixed Correspondence, 1961-1969, 1984, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Mixed Correspondence, 1962-1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Letters, 1962-2005 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Letters 2, 1963-2013 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Mixed Correspondence, 1962-1966, 1971-1982, 1987-1988, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence & Miscellaneous, 1965-2014 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Letters, 1970-1996 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1971-2003 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      Includes Gauri Deshpande's letters regarding the "boycott on a USIS programme taking part in 1971" (Bangladesh Liberation War)
    - Writing/Non-Writing Correspondence 2, 1973-2010 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Letters, 1977-1983, 1987, 1992, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Writing/Non-Writing Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      Includes an apology letter addressed to "Farida Peddar" (1986)
    - Correspondence concerning paintings/painters, Bhuphen, etc. and Articles on War from 1999, 1980-1989, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Writing/Non-Writing Correspondence 3, 1990-1999 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Letters & Flickr Catalogue, 1998-2011 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Writing/Non-Writing Correspondence 4, 2000-2009 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Writer Files, 1993, 1998, 2000-2002, 2006-2007, 2010-2011
  - Mulk Raj Anand File, 1969-2006 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Lawrence Bantleman File, 1972-1998, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Homi K. Bhabha File, 1971-2014 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Dhiren Bhagat File, 1982-2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Amit Chaudhuri clippings, 1991, 1998-2004, 2007-2009, 2011, 2015 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Ashay Chitre File, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Dilip Chitre File, 1968-2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dilip Chitre File, 1970-2012 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Eunice de Souza File, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Farrukh Dhondy File, 1968-1969, 1979, 1989, 1994, 2014-2016 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Nissim Ezekiel File, 1940-2004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gopal Honnalgere File, 1969-2011 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Attia Hosain, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Arun Kolatkar File, 1970-2009 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Arun Kolatkar File, 1977-2013 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Arvind Krishna Mehrotra File, 1977, 1983, 2003-2004, 2011-2013 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dom Moraes File, 1964-2013 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - H.O. Nazareth File, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - R. Raj Rao File, 1978, 1991-1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Santan Rodrigues File, 1978-1979, 2005-2009 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Beram Saklatvala File, 1945, 1954, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Vilas Sarang File, 1980, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Vilas Sarang File, 1972-2015 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Mala Sen File, 1998-12-2016-05-30 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Sudhir Sonalkar File, 1972, 1982, 1988-1989, 2002-2007, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tehelka: 2000; Ashley Tellis, Eunice de Souza, Raj Rao, and Adil Jussawalla File, 2000-07-12-2000-12-07 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Literary Work by Adil Jussawalla, 1951-2012
  - Specific Works, 1951-2012
    - Distance in Statute Miles Manuscript, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - The Borderer Magazine Copies, 1951-12-1956-12 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      Annual editions published in month of December
    - The Borderer Printed Scans, 1952-12-1956-12 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Jian: A Rebellion play, 1958-11-20 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Floodwaters play, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Speeches and Articles, 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Afro-Asian Echo Magazines, December 24, 1965-January 6, 1966, January 7-13, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Drafts of Unfinished Novel Strays, 1967, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Train to Calcutta Commentary and Contract, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Manuscripts of Published Work, 1970, 1973, 1983-1985, 1990, 1993-2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Interviews by Adil Jussawalla, 1985, 1989, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Interviews with Adil Jussawalla, 1986-2012 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Article on Rushdie for UNESCO Courier, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Chakravyuha Working Scripts and Reviews, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Apart From All That Clippings, 1988-08-1991-06 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Manuscripts of Published Work 1, 1991-2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Manuscripts of Published Work 2, 1996-2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Assorted Clippings, 1970-2012
    - Clippings of Published Work, 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Clippings of Published Work, 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Clippings of Published Work, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Clippings of Published Work, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Clippings of Published Work, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Clippings of Published Work, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Clippings of Published Work, 2000-2002 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Clippings of Published Work, 2003-2012 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Clippings of Published Work, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Writing by Others, 1956-2015
  - Clippings and Articles, 1956-2015
    - London/Great Britain Clippings, 1956-2008 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Articles on Writers, 1961-2001 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Criticism of Indians Writing in English, 1962-2008 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Bombay/India Clippings, 1963-1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1963-2006 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Culture Clippings, 1963-2007 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Clippings about Indian writers/writing 3, 1964-2013 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - New Statesman and The Century on Commonwealth Literature, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Culture Clippings, 1965-2008 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Clippings about Indian writers/writing 4, 1965-2010 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Clippings about Indian writers/writing 2, 1965-2012 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Assorted Clippings, 1965-2013 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Clippings about Indian writers/writing, 1965-2014 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Clippings about Indian and Pakistani writers and poets, 1966-2015 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Bombay Clippings, 1967-2005 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Culture Clippings, 1968-2006 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook w/ Clippings, 1970-1978 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Articles concerning Indian writers/other writing, 1966, 1975-1980, 1991-1999, 2005-2008, 2015 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Reviews of Arun Kolatkar"s Jejuri, 1976-1979, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Indian Express lock-out, 1976-1993 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      Includes information on a boycott of the Indian Express newspaper publication
    - Articles concerning Kersy Katrak, 1976, 1981-1983, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Articles concerning Indian writing/other writing 2, 1993-2006 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Literary Works, 1961-2004
    - And Then the Sun by Pradeep Sen, Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - David McCutchion miscellaneous works, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Most likely written between 1957-1972
    - Poems by Rajeev Patke, Undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - S. Anand poetry manuscript, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Clearing House - Writing and Reviews, 1961-1978 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Lawrence Bantleman Poems, 1962, 1967-1969, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Copies of Work by P. Lal and Sachin Ketkar, 1962, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Lawrence Bantleman Articles in The Century, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Indian writing assortment, 1968-2003 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Kersy Katrak's Manuscript of Five Little Sermons Went to Market, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Raul D'Gama Rose Manuscripts of Poems, 1975-1982 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Learning to Drown by Vivek Narayanan, 1999-03 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Literary Publications, 1968, 1989, 1995-1997, 2001-2003
    - Beloit Poetry Journal and Carcanet, Winter 1962-63, Fall 1965, Winter 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Aso Literary Journal, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Ed. Ashok Shahane; Pune, India: Sangam Press
    - Kavi - The Forum for Indian Poetry, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Literary Newsletters, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Zerohour, 1990-06 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Vol. 2 No. 2
    - BEAM - Bombay English Association Magazine, July 1991, August 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bhubaneswar Review, Summer 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Bombay, March 7-21, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Brown Critique, October - December 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Chandana, February - April 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Commonwealth Quarterly, 1987-12-1988-03 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Crimson Feet, 2004-07 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Dialogue Calcutta, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Dialogue India, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Expression India, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Five + One, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - The Giraffe Flames, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Indian Literature, July - August 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Indian Verse, Winter 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Kavya Bharati (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Khela (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Literary Endeavour, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - The Literary Criterion, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - The Literary Review, 1986-06-1986-08 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Poetry Chain, Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Poetry Chronicle, 1990-01-1992-04 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Rupambara, 1969-08-1969-09 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Spark, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Personal Writing and Documents, 1944-2013
  - Diaries, 1955-2013
    - Personal Diaries, 1955-1960, 2013 (Box 5)
    - Date Book, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Scrapbook, 1967-2008 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Academic Related Materials and Certificates, 1944-1999
    - Academic Exercise Books, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Cathedral School- class reports, kindergarten onwards, 1944-1956 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Also contains grade reports for Adil Jussawalla's brother, Firdausi
    - Royal Society of Music Certificates and Comments, 1950-1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Cathedral School materials, 1952-1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - School certificate, 1952-04-24 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - School Exercise Books and Essays, 1954-1956, 1961-1962, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Certificates, 1955-1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - St. Xavier's College related (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - T.S. Eliot Seminar at University of Allahabad, 1989-02-1989-03 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Tape Recordings, 1955, 1957, 1964-1965, 1968, 1977, 1983
  - New Writing in India, 1974-05-02; TR-10923 (Box 5)
  - Adil Jussawalla Interviewed by Peter Nazareth 1, 1977-12; TR-10924 (Box 5)
  - Adil Jussawalla Interviewed by Peter Nazareth 2, 1977-12; TR-10925 (Box 5)
  - Horace Ove Interviewed by Adil Jussawalla, Undated; TR-10926 (Box 5)
  - Poetry Reading in London, 1969-1970; TR-10927 (Box 5)
  - Poetry Reading in Singapore, 1986; TR-10928 (Box 5)
  - Loquations presents An Evening for Arun, 2004-05-10; TR-10929 (Box 5)
  - English Poetry from India, Undated; TR-10930 (Box 5)
  - Chakravyuha I Trial Run, Undated; TR-10931 (Box 5)
  - Chakravyuha II Trial Run, Undated; TR-10932 (Box 5)
  - Wignesan, Undated; TR-10933 (Box 5)
- Assorted Files, 1965-1992
  - Sameeksha contents page, 1965-12 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Students & Teacher's Movements, 1967-1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Film work file, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Teachers' Protests, 1971-1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Students & Famine, 1972-1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Greater Bombay Writer's Conference Information, 1971, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous file, 1983-1992 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    Contains two correspondences and one clipping detailed "Last Summer"
  - Frankfurt Bookfair Information, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 21)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Sarang, Vilas. Seven Critical Essays, Undated
Mahapatra, Jayanta. The False Start, 1980
Nazareth, H.O. Lobo, 1984
Menen, Rajendar. Nature Cure: Dr. J.M. Jussawalla's Drugless Healing, 2013
Reuben, Bunny. Monkeys on the Hill of God, 1985
Ed. Bhalla, Alok; Verma, Nirmal; Ananthamurthy, U. R. Yatra, 1993
Ed. Bhalla, Alok; Verma, Nirmal; Ananthamurthy, U. R. Yatra 2, 1994
Pritish Nandy, TR. The Poetry of Kaifi Azmi, 1975
Bandekar, Prakash. I am India' and a Few Other Poems, Undated
Chitre, Dilip; Jussawalla, Adil. The Reasoning Vision: Jehangir Sabavala's Painterly Universe, 1980
Nazareth, H.O. Lobo